Liel Amar

E-mailliel@lielamar.comDate of birthMarch 18th, 2001Websitelielamar.comMobile+972 (54) 974-1803GitHubgithub.com/LielAmarAddressGilo, Jerusalem

A 2nd-year Computer Science student and an expert developer with 7+ years of experience in various languages, technologies, large-scale systems, and applications. A natural leader with proven capabilities in team management, public assistance, employee nurturing and tutoring, and creating and executing work plans. Creative, inquisitive, and autodidact.

Professional Experience

March 2015 - Present

Software Developer | Freelancer

- Developed various software, including Desktop and Web Applications, and Plugins, for clients, using Java, TypeScript, and Python.
- Developed public libraries in various languages, including Java & TypeScript.

July 2022 - October 2022

Summer Internship - Software Developer | Oversight, Israel

- Maintained and implemented new features for a B2B startup using NodeJS.
- Worked in a team and collaborated with other employees on a daily basis.
- participated in meetings with clients and provided technical evaluations.

January 2021 - August 2021

Software Developer | ReWrite Media, Remote

- Developed games, cosmetics, and tools for Minecraft servers, using Spigot & Velocity.
- Designed UI and implemented Web applications using Java's Spring Boot, NodeJS with Express & React, and AWS.
- Integrated Redis, MongoDB, and RabbitMQ to existing software.
- Worked in a team and collaborated with other employees on a daily basis.

August 2019 - April 2020

Developer, Unit Co-Founder | Israel Defense Forces, Israel

- Designed, implemented, tested, deployed, and maintained a real-time location-based Web application and secured software in the IDF network.
- Provided units with evaluations, demonstrations, and samples.
- Collaborated with other brigades, and shared resources, and knowledge.

July 2017 - July 2019

Developer, Video Editor | Oversight, Israel

- Maintained 20 Game servers on Linux and Windows machines.
- Designed and developed 7 large-scale games within the Minecraft engine.
- Led weekly development meetings and monthly meetings with teams of volunteers.

Volunteer Positions

July 2019 - May 2021

Staff Member, Mentor | Hypixel, Remote

- Provided in-game assistance to players and general moderation.
- Trained and mentored new staff members.
- Found bugs and tested new updates, features, and games.

Education and Languages

October 2021 - Present

Bachelor's in Computer Science | The Hebrew University of Jerusalem

- 2nd-year student
- GPA: 90.6

September 2016- June 2019

High-School, Emphasis on Computer Science & Physics | Ort's College

• GPA: 115.3

Hebrew - Native language

English - Fluent speaker